One of the things that
واحد من الأشياء التي
defines a TEDster
تعرّف عضو تيد
is you've taken your passion,
أنك أخذت شغفك،
and you've turned it into stewardship.
وحولته الى اشراف.
You actually put action to the issues you care about.
أنت في الواقع تقوم بجهد تجاه القضايا التي تهمّك.
But what you're going to find eventually is
لكن ما ستجده في النهاية هو
you may need to actually get elected officials
أنك تحتاج الى مسؤولين منتخبين
to help you out.
لمساعدتك.
So, how do you do that?
اذا، كيف تفعل ذلك؟
One of the things I should probably tell you is,
واحد من الأشياء الي يمكن أن اقولها لكم هي،
I worked for the Discovery Channel early in my career,
عملت لقناة ديسكفري مبكرا في مهنتي،
and that sort of warped my framework.
وذلك غلّف اطار عملي نوعا ما.
So, when you start to think about politicians,
اذا، عندما تبدأ بالتفكير عن السياسيين،
you've got to realize these are strange creatures.
عليك أن تستنتج أن هؤلاء مخلوقات غريبة.
Other than the fact that they can't tell directions,
ناهيك عن حقيقة أنهم لا يقدرون على وصف الاتجاهات،
and they have very strange breeding habits,
ولديهم عادات تربوية غريبة جدا،
how do you actually work with these things? (Laughter)
حقيقة كيف تتعامل مع هذه الأشياء؟
What we need to understand is:
ما علينا فهمه هو:
What drives the political creature?
ما الذي يقود المخلوقات السياسية؟
And there are two things that are primary in a politician's heart:
وهناك شيئان أساسيان في قلب السياسي.
One is reputation and influence.
واحد، السُمعة والنفوذ.
These are the primary tools by which
هذه أدوات أساسية من خلالها
a politician can do his job.
يستطيع السياسي القيام بعمله.
The second one -- unlike most animals,
الثانية، عكس معظم الحيوانات،
which is survival of the species --
هي حفظ النوع،
this is preservation of self.
هذه هي حماية النفس.
Now you may think it's money,
الآن يمكن أن تعتقد أنه المال،
but that's actually sort of a proxy
لكن هذا في الحقيقة نوع من الوكالة
to what I can do to preserve myself.
لما يمكن ان أعمله لأحفظ نفسي
Now, the challenge with you moving your issue forward
الآن، التحدي معك في تحريك قضيتك للأمام
is these animals are getting broadcast to all the time.
هي أن هذه الحيوانات تلقى اعلاما طوال الوقت.
So, what doesn't work, in terms of getting your issue to be important?
اذا، ما الذي لا ينجح ، في جعل قضيتك مهمة؟
You can send them an email.
بامكانك ارسال بريد الكتروني لهم.
Well, unfortunately, I've got so many
حسنا، لسوء الحظ، لدي الكثير
Viagra ads coming at me,
من رسائل اعلانات فياغرا تصلني،
your email is lost.
وقد ضاعت رسالة بريدك الاكتروني .
It doesn't matter, it's spam.
هذا لا يهم، انها رسائل مزعجة.
How about you get on the phone?
ماذا لو اتصلت عبر الهاتف؟
Well, chances are I've got a droid who's picking up the phone,
حسنا، الفرص هي أنه لدي روبوت يرفع السماعة،
"Yes, they called, and they said they didn't like it."
"نعم، لقد اتصلوا، وقد قالوا أنهم لم يعجبهم."
That doesn't move.
هذا لا يحرّك ساكناً.
Face to face would work,
وجها لوجه قد تنجح،
but it's hard to set it up.
لكن من الصعب تحضير الوضع.
It's hard to get the context and actually get the communication to work.
من الصعب أن تحصل على سياق الكلام و التواصل فعليا للعمل.
Yes, contributions actually do make a difference
نعم، المساهمات تقوم بإحداث تغيير فعلا،
and they set a context for having a conversation,
وهي تجهّز سياق للكلام للنقاش،
but it takes some time to build up.
لكنها تستغرق بعض الوقت في التحضير لها.
So what actually works?
اذا ما الذي ينجح حقا؟
And the answer is rather strange.
والإجابة غريبة الى حد ما.
It's a letter.
انها رسالة.
We live in a digital world,
نحن نعيش في عالم رقمي،
but we're fairly analog creatures.
لكننا مخلوقات تناظّرية بكل وضوح.
Letters actually work.
الرسائل تنجح فعليا.
Even the top dog himself
حتى لمن هو أعلى القمة
takes time every day to read 10 letters
يقضي وقت كل يوم لقراءة 10 رسائل
that are picked out by staff.
التي يجلبها الموظفون.
I can tell you that every official that I've ever worked with
أستطيع أن أقول لكم أن كل مسؤول رسمي عملت معه
will tell you about the letters they get
سوف يخبركم عن الرسائل التي تصلهم
and what they mean.
وماذا تعني لهم.
So, how are you going to write your letter?
اذا، كيف سوف تكتب رسالتك؟
First of all, you're going to pick up an analog device: a pen.
أولا، سوف تحضر أداة كتابية، قلم.
I know these are tough, and you may have a hard time
أنا أعلم أنه صعب، وقد تواجه وقتا عصيبا
getting your hand bent around it, (Laughter)
في جعل يدك تلتف حوله،
but this is actually critical.
لكن هذا فعلا ضروري.
And it is critical that
وانه ضروري أن
you actually handwrite your letter.
تكتب رسالتك بخط يدك.
It is so novel to see this,
انه غير مألوف جدا أن ترى هذا،
that somebody actually picked up an analog device
أن أحدا فعلا أمسك أداة كتابة
and has written to me.
وكتب لي.
Second of all, I'm going to recommend that
ثانيا، سوف أوصي بأن
you get into a proactive stance
تقوم بموقف استباقي
and write to your elected officials at least once a month.
وتكتب للمسؤولين المنتخبين مرة على الأقل كل شهر.
Here's my promise to you:
ها هو وعدي لكم.
If you are consistent and do this,
اذا أصريتم أن تفعلوا هذا،
within three months the elected official will start calling you
خلال ثلاثة شهور سيبدأ المسؤول المنتخب بالاتصال بكم.
when that issue comes up and say, "What do you think?"
عندما تبرز تلك القضية، وتقول، "ما رأيك؟"
Now, I'm going to give you
الآن، سوف أعطيكم
a four paragraph format to work with.
صيغة من أربع فقرات للعمل عليها.
Now, when you approach these animals,
الآن، عندما تقتربون من هذه الحيوانات،
you need to understand there's a dangerous end to them,
عليكم أن تفهموا، توجد مآلات خطرة بالنسبة لهم،
and you also need to approach them
وعليكم أيضا أن تقترب اليهم
with some level of respect and a little bit of wariness.
مع درجة من الاحترام وقليل من الحذر.
So in paragraph number one,
اذا في الفقرة رقم واحد،
what I'm going to tell you to do is very simply this:
ما سأقول لكم أن تفعلوه بسيط جدا:
You appreciate them.
قدم إحترامك.
You may not appreciate the person, you may not appreciate anything else,
قد لا تحترم الشخص، قد لا تحترم أي شيء أخر،
but maybe you appreciate the fact that they've got a tough gig.
لكن ربما تحترمون واقع أنهم حصلوا على ضجيج كبير.
When animals are going to make a point, they make the point.
عندما تكون الحيوانات تريد إثبات نقطة، فانها تثبتها.
They don't spend a lot of time dicking around.
انهم لا يقضون الكثير من الوقت في الحفر.
So, here you go. (Laughter)
اذا، ها نحن ننطلق.
Paragraph number two:
الفقرة رقم اثنان،
You may actually have to just get very blunt
عليك فعلا أن تصبح بليد جدا
and say what's really on your mind.
وتقول ما يجول في خاطرك فعلا.
When you do this,
عندما تقوم بهذا،
don't attack people;
لا تهاجم الناس،
you attack tactics.
أنت تهاجم التكتيكات.
Ad hominem attacks will get you nowhere.
هجوم الاعلام سوف يوصلك الى لامكان.
Paragraph number three:
الفقرة رقم ثلاثة:
When animals are attacked or cornered,
عندما تهاجم الحيوانات أو تنزنق في الناصية،
they will fight to the death,
سوف تقاتل حتى الموت،
so you have to give them an exit.
لذا عليكم اعطائهم مخرج.
Most of the time, if they have an exit strategy, they should take it.
معظم الوقت، اذا كان لديهم مخرج استراتيجي، عليهم أن يأخذوه.
"Obviously, you're intelligent.
بشكل واضح، أنت عبقري.
If you had the right information,
اذا كان لديك المعلومة الصحيحة،
you would have done the right thing." (Laughter)
تكون قد فعلت الأمر الصواب.
Lastly, you want to be the nurturing agent.
أخيرا، تريد أن تكون خبير التغذية.
You're the safe place to come in to.
أنت المكان الآمن للمجيء اليه.
So, in paragraph number four,
اذا، الفقرة رقم أربعة،
you're going to tell people,
سوف تقول للناس،
"If no one is providing you with this information, let me help." (Laughter)
"اذا لم يزودك أحد بهذه المعلومة، دعني أساعد."
Animals do displays. They do two things:
تقوم الحيوانات بالتباهي. انهم يفعلون شيئين.
They warn you or they try to attract you
يحذرونك أو يحاولون إستمالتك
and say, "We need to mate."
ويقولون، "علينا إنشاء صداقة؟"
You're going to do that by the way you sign your letter.
سوف تقوم بفعل ذلك عندما توقع رسالتك.
You do a number of things: you're a vice president,
أنت تعمل عدد من الأمور، أنت نائب رئيس،
you volunteer, you do something else.
أنت تتطوع، أنت تفعل شيء آخر.
Why is is this important?
لماذا هذا مهم؟
Because this establishes the two
لأن هذا يؤسس
primary criteria for the political creature:
الطريقتين الأساسيتين للكائن السياسي،
that you have influence in a large sphere,
أن لديك تأثير على محيط واسع،
and that my preservation depends on you.
ووجودي يعتمد عليك.
Here is one very quick hack,
هذه واحدة من طرق الاختراق السريعة،
especially for the feds in the audience.
خاصة للزملاء ضمن الحضور.
Here's how you mail your letter.
بهذه الكيفية ارسل رسالتك.
First of all, you send the original to the district office.
أولا، ترسل النسخة الأصلية لمكتب المقاطعة،
So, you send the copy to the main office.
اذا ترسل النسخة للمكتب الرئيسي.
If they follow protocol, they'll pick up the phone and say, "Hey, do you have the original?"
اذا كانوا يتبعون البروتوكول، سوف يرفعون الهاتف ويقولون، " هل لديك الأصلية؟"
Then some droid in the back puts the name on a tickler
ثم روبوت "شخص ما" في الخلف يضع الاسم شريط
and says, "Oh, this is an important letter."
ويقول، "أوه، هذه رسالة مهمة."
And you actually get into the folder
وأنت فعلا تدخل الى الملف
that the elected official actually has to read.
الذي على المسؤول المنتخب أن يقرأه.
So, what your letter means:
اذا، ماذا تعني رسالتك؟
I've got to tell you, we are all in a party,
عليّ أن أقول لك، نحن جميعا في حفلة،
and political officials are the pinatas.
والرسميون السيايون هم الديكورات.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We are harangued, lectured to,
نحن خاطبنا، إلقينا محاضرة إلى،
sold, marketed,
بعنا، سوقّنا،
but a letter is actually one of the few times
لكن الرسالة هي واحدة من الأوقات القليلة
that we have honest communication.
التي يكون لدينا تواصل صادق.
I got this letter when I was first elected,
وصلتني هذه الرسالة عندما انتخبت أول مرة،
and I still carry it to
وما زلت أحملها الى
every council meeting I go to.
أي اجتماع مجلس أذهب اليه.
This is an opportunity at real dialogue,
هذه فرصة لحوار حقيقي.
and if you have stewardship
واذا كان لديك الإهتمام
and want to communicate,
وأردت التواصل،
that dialogue is incredibly powerful.
هذا الحوار فعال بشكل رائع.
So when you do that, here's what I can promise:
اذاً عندما تقوم بذلك، هذا ما أعدك به:
You're going to be the 800 pound gorilla in the forest.
سوف تكون في مقام الغوريلا التي تزن 800 باوند في الغابة.
Get writing.
ابدأ بالكتابة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)